<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfFeat xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Armour Proficiency (Light)</Name>
    <Prerequisites></Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>Ignore armour check penalty</Abstract>
    <Benefit>When you wear a type of armour with which you are proficient, you can ignore the
armour check penalty to attacks and Ride checks.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You have trained in the use of light armour, learning how best to move and fight in
leather or cloth armours (see Table 11-8, Armour, page 213)</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Armour Proficiency (Medium)</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Armour Proficiency (Light)</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>Ignore armour check penalty</Abstract>
    <Benefit>When you wear a type of armour with which you are proficient, you can ignore the
armour check penalty to attacks and Ride checks.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You have trained in the use of medium armour, learning how best to move and fight in
mail (see Table 11-8, Armour, page 213)</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Accuracy</Name>
    <Prerequisites>BAB +4</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT difficulty penalty -2</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You suffer reduced dice penalties when attempting difficult attacks, such as striking
at weak points, vital spots, or shooting at long ranges. Accuracy also comes into play when
attempting a special trick shot, such as carving an initial on someone’s body or pinning
a target’s clothing to a wall with an arrow. This Feat reduces the difficulty penalty of any
appropriate attack by 2 (to a minimum of 0). For example, attacking a vital spot (-8 penalty)
now incurs a -6 penalty, while firing at double range (-4 penalty) would receive -2 penalty. For
more information on trick shots and attacking vital spots, see page 241. Additionally, if your
opponents is defending with a shield, you get a +2 bonus to attack as long as you are trying to
bypass the shield (rather than strike it).</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>A keen eye and steady hand let you attack with uncanny accuracy.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Accuracy (Improved)</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Accuracy
BAB + 8</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT difficulty penalty -2</Abstract>
    <Benefit>As with Accuracy, you suffer reduced dice penalties when attempting difficult attacks,
such as striking at weak points or vital spots, or shooting at long ranges. Each difficulty penalty
is reduced by an additional 2 points (to a minimum of 0). For example, attacking a vital spot
(-8 penalty) incurs a -4 penalty, while firing at double range (-4 penalty) would receive 0 penalty.
For more information on trick shots and attacking vital spots, see page 241. Additionally, if
your opponents is defending with a shield, you get a further +2 bonus (+4 total) to attack as
long as you are trying to bypass the shield (rather than strike it).</Benefit>
    <Special>This Feat stacks with the bonuses provided by Accuracy, for a total penalty reduction
of -4.</Special>
    <Description>Your technique with melee or ranged weapons is near perfect, allowing amazing displays
of accuracy and pinpoint targeting.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Authority</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Cha 13</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>+1 Reputation &amp; Influcence</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You are well-known for your prominent rank and gain a +1 bonus to all 
Reputation checks. Additionally, you gain a +1 to all Influence checks.</Benefit>
    <Special>This feat must be approved by the GM, and must be appropriate to the story or
plotline of the ongoing campaig.n</Special>
    <Description>Through birth, merit or appointment, you have earned a position of prominence
in your house, clan, or community. Your position brings with it both public recognition and
political influence.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Aware</Name>
    <Prerequisites>BAB +3</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>never flat-footed</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You recover quickly from surprise attacks, and are thus never caught
flat-footed (see page 250). If you are surprised, the attacker still receives one
free surprise attack round - but your are not flat-footed during this time.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description></Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Blind Fighting</Name>
    <Prerequisites></Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You suffer only half the normal penalties associated with attacking or
defending with melee weapons or while unarmed in poor light, absolute darkness, or against
an unseen opponent (s. page 248 more information about darkness penalties).</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You've learned how to use your ears and finely-honed senses to fight in
melee without being able to see your foe.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Bravado</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Cha 13</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT or PA + Cha bonus</Abstract>
    <Benefit>Select one weapon. When using that weapon, you may opt to add your Cha
bonus to attack rolls or defence rolls, chosen when this feat is selected.</Benefit>
    <Special>This feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to either the
alternate value (attack or defence) or a different weapon. Its effects do not stack with
Brute, Canny, Finesse or Tactics.</Special>
    <Description>Your Charisma allows you to dominate opponents through sheer presence
and force of will.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Armour Proficiency (Heavy)</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Armour Proficiency (Light)
Armour Proficiency (Medium)</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>Ignore armour check penalty</Abstract>
    <Benefit>When you wear a type of armour with which you are proficient, you can ignore the
armour check penalty to attacks and Ride checks.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You have trained in the use of heavy armour, learning how best to move and fight in
heavy mail and plate (see Table 11-8, Armour, page 213)</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Brawl</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Str 13</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT +1
nonlethal dam D6 +  Str modifier</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You receive a +1 bonus to hit when attacking unarmed, and you deal nonlethal damage
equal to 1d6 + your Strength Modifier.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You’re no stranger to a brawl. Strength, practice, and ferocity have made your bare
knuckles into formidable weapons.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Brawl (Improved)</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Brawl
BAB +3</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT +2
nonlethal dam D8 +  Str modifier</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You receive a +2 bonus when attacking unarmed, and you deal nonlethal damage equal
to 1d8 + your Strength Modifier.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You are a dedicated brawler, and are a terror even without weapons.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Brute</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Str 13</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT or PA +Str bonus</Abstract>
    <Benefit>Select one weapon. When using that weapon in melee, you may opt to add your Str
bonus to attack rolls or defence rolls, chosen when this Feat is first selected.</Benefit>
    <Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to either the alternate
value (attack or defence) or a different weapon. Its effects do not stack with Bravado, Canny,
Finesse, or Tactics.</Special>
    <Description>Your Strength allows you to handle a heavy weapon with ease. You may lack finesse and
technique, but you compensate with raw power.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Canny</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Wis 13</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT or PA +Wis bonus</Abstract>
    <Benefit>Select one weapon. When using that weapon, you may opt to add your Wis bonus to
attack rolls or defence rolls, chosen when this Feat is first selected.</Benefit>
    <Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to either the alternate
value (attack or defence) or a different weapon. Its effects do not stack with Bravado, Brute,
Finesse, or Tactics.</Special>
    <Description>Your Wisdom allows you to fight strategically.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Cleave</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Str 13
Power Attack</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>Extra AT</Abstract>
    <Benefit>If, in a single attack, you deal enough damage to a foe to make him or her drop (by
reducing the foe to 0 Hit Points, slaying the foe, overcoming a foe’s Shock Value, etc.), you
get an immediate, extra melee attack on another foe within reach. You cannot move before
making this extra attack. The extra attack is made with the same weapon and same attack
bonus as the attack that dropped the previous foe. You may use this ability only once in a
combat round.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>In combat, you can follow through successful hits with powerful blows.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Cleave (Great)</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Str 13
Power Attack
Cleave
BAB +4</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>Multiple extra AT</Abstract>
    <Benefit>As per Cleave, except that there is no limit to the number of free Cleave attacks you can
make in a round. You may not take any movement between the free Cleave attacks.</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You can wield a melee weapon with such power that you can strike multiple times
whenever you fell your foes.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Combat Agility</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Str 13
Power Attack
Cleave
Dex 13
Int 13
Combat Expertise
Dodge</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>Second defence roll</Abstract>
    <Benefit>You may make a second defence roll in a single round at your full Defence Bonus,
ignoring the normal penalty for defending against multiple attackers. See Defending Against
Multiple Attacks, page 249 for more information.</Benefit>
    <Special>You may take this Feat multiple times. Each time, you can make an additional defence
roll at full bonus. You may only take this Feat a number of times equal to your Dex bonus.</Special>
    <Description>Your reflexes and awareness allow you to maintain an uncanny defence in combat,
keeping your guard up even against several opponents.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Combat Expertise</Name>
    <Prerequisites>Int 13</Prerequisites>
    <Abstract>AT -x -&gt; PA +x</Abstract>
    <Benefit>On an attack action in melee, you can take a penalty of as much as -5 to your attack
rolls, and add that same number (up to +5) to your defence roll. The number of points shifted
from attack to defence cannot exceed the character’s Base Attack Bonus. The bonus to defence
applies until the character’s next action, and is a dodge bonus. This Feat is different from
fighting defensively, and supersedes those bonuses (see page 245 for more information).</Benefit>
    <Special></Special>
    <Description>You have trained in using your combat skills for defence as well as offence.</Description>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Command</Name>
<Description>You have been given command of an organisation, and have control over its Wealth
and Influences.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Member of the organisation
GM’s approval</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>Wealth +1
Social Status checks +2 bonus</Abstract>
<Benefit>You are the acknowledged Lord Commander (or equivalent title, such as High Septon
or Grand Maester) of an organisation. Your Wealth increases by +1 Rank. You also gain +2 to
all checks where Social Status applies (such as Influence checks and Social Skill rolls), since
people recognise your authority. Additionally, the Maximum Influence over your organisation
increases by 10 (you do not receive any more Influence Points, but you can spend more to
establish greater control. For example, the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard would have
Social Status Rank 4 and Maximum Influence of 50 over the Kingsguard, while the Lord
Commander of the Night’s Watch would have Social Status Rank 3 and Maximum Influence
of 40 over the Night’s Watch).</Benefit>
<Special>Your title may need to be confirmed by a greater authority (the king, the members of
the organisation, etc.). In your territory, you have the potential for tremendous power (see
Maximum Influence, page 191), and you may have other rights and privileges, depending on
your organisation’s position.
This Feat should not be used to gain control over a noble house (see Heir and Head
of House).</Special>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Critical (Improved)</Name>
<Description>Your mastery of one type of weapon makes you deadly in combat. When wielding that
weapon, you know exactly where to strike your opponents to cripple or slay them.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Base Attack Bonus +8
Proficiency with the chosen weapon</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>double critical threat range</Abstract>
<Benefit>Choose one type of weapon. When using that weapon, the critical threat range is
doubled. For example, a longsword usually threatens a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 (a 2 in
20 chance). If you take Critical (Improved) with longswords, the threat range expands to 17
to 20 (a 4 in 20 chance).</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times, but its effects do not stack. Each additional
application of this Feat applies to a different weapon.</Special>
  </Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Dodge</Name>
<Description>You are adept at dodging blows.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Dex 13</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+1 dodge bonus</Abstract>
<Benefit>At the beginning of each combat round, designate an opponent and receive a +1 dodge bonus
to all defence rolls made against that opponent. You may select a new opponent every action. Any
condition that makes you lose your Dex bonus to defence rolls (being caught flat-footed, etc.),
negates this and all other dodge bonuses. Dodge Feat bonuses stack with other dodge bonuses.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Its effects stack up to a maximum bonus of +3
or your Dex bonus, whichever is lower.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Endurance</Name>
<Description>You are capable of amazing feats of stamina.</Description>
<Abstract>+4 bonus physcial actions</Abstract><Benefit>Whenever making an extended check for any physical action (running, swimming, etc.), you
receive a +4 bonus. Also, you may sleep in light or medium armour without becoming fatigued. If
the optional Fatigue rules (page 256) are being used, Endurance reduces your Fatigue Value by 1.</Benefit>
<Special>If using the Fatigue Over Time optional rule (page 257), Endurance increases the
number of rounds you can fight by +4.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Fame</Name>
<Description>For whatever reason, you are particularly well known.</Description>
<Abstract>+2 Reputation</Abstract><Benefit>You receive a bonus of +2 Reputation Points. These Points can be added to an existing
Reputation (or divided between two Reputations), or used to acquire a new Reputation.</Benefit>
<Special>You may select this Feat multiple times. Its effects stack.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Far Shot</Name>
<Description>You can get greater distance than normal out of a ranged weapon.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>increase range increment</Abstract><Benefit>When you use a projectile weapon, the range increment of any missile weapon is
increased. Missile weapons (like bows and crossbows) increase their range increments by 50%
(multiply by 1.5). When you use a thrown weapon, its range increment is doubled.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Fast Healer</Name>
<Description>An iron constitution and remarkable stamina allow you to recover from injuries and
illness at an amazing rate.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Con 13</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>recover twice/three times as normal</Abstract><Benefit>You recover from all forms of damage (Hit Points, Ability damage, and subdual
damage) at twice the normal rate. Any circumstances that increase the rate of natural healing
(long term care arising from the Heal Skill, for example) increase your natural healing rate to
three times the normal rate if resting, or twice the normal rate if you continue to be active. See
page 258 for information on healing wounds.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may only be taken at 1st Level.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Favoured</Name>
<Description>You have gained the attention and favour of a powerful noble. His or her good will lends
weight to your presence, and this noble’s influence can open the door to many opportunities.</Description>
<Abstract>+2 bonus Diplomacy/Intimidate</Abstract><Benefit>You receive a +2 circumstance bonus to Diplomacy and Intimidate checks, as
appropriate to the situation. Additionally, this Feat offsets one Affiliation or Class requirement
for a Class, Feat, or Prestige Class. For example, even though Sandor Clegane had no Levels
in the Knight Prestige Class, Joffrey’s favour was enough to award him membership in the
Kingsguard (and access to the Prestige Class).</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat requires the presence of a noble ally or patron for the character within the
story, and may only be taken with GM approval.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Finesse</Name>
<Description>Your nimbleness and agility allow you to make lighting-quick strikes.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Dex 13</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>AT + Dex bonus</Abstract><Benefit>Select one weapon. When using that weapon, you may opt to add your Dex bonus to
attack or defence rolls, chosen when this Feat is first selected.</Benefit>
<Special>
This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to either the alternate value (attack
or defence) or a different weapon. Its effects do not stack with Bravado, Brute, Canny, or Tactics.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Fortune’s Favour</Name>
<Description>You have always been blessed with a strong lucky streak.</Description>
<Abstract>reroll one die/day</Abstract><Benefit>Once per game day, you may reroll any one die roll just made, as long as the outcome
of the roll depends more upon luck than Skill. Craft, Profession, and Knowledge Skills, for
example, rely primarily upon Skill, while Listen or Search checks involve more chance. Will
and Fortitude Saves rarely depend upon luck, but Reflex Saves often do. Attack rolls and
damage rolls involve enough chance to invoke this Feat.
You may always try to frame an action in such a way as to emphasise the role of chance
or luck in the outcome; the GM, however, is always the final arbiter as to whether or not this
Feat applies. With GM approval, the player may make the roll over again and choose the more
beneficial of the two results.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each additional time you take the Feat, you may
make one additional reroll per day.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Great Fortitude</Name>
<Description>You are tougher than normal.</Description>
<Abstract>+2 bonus Fortitude saves</Abstract><Benefit>You gain a +2 bonus to all Fortitude Saves.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Hard Luck</Name>
<Abstract>reroll natural 1</Abstract><Benefit>Your life has been fraught with hardship, but through perseverance and tenacity you
always seem to pull through. Whenever you get a natural 1 on a Saving Throw, attack roll, or
defence check, you get an immediate bonus non-attack action. The effects are more or less
simultaneous; you should be able to react before the full negative effect is felt. For example,
if you rolled a critical failure on an attack roll you could move back, draw a new weapon, etc.
If you failed a Saving Throw with a natural 1 you could similarly attempt to retreat out of
harm’s way.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Head of House</Name>
<Description>You are the head of a noble house, commanding all of its Wealth and Influences.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Heir
GM’s approval</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>Wealth +1
+2 Social Status checks
Max Influence +10</Abstract><Benefit>You are the acknowledged lord or lady of a powerful house. Your Wealth increases by +1
Rank. You also gain +2 to all checks where Social Status applies (such as Influence checks and
Social Skill rolls), as people recognise your authority. Additionally, the Maximum Influence
over your house increases by 10 (you do not receive any more Influence Points, but you can
spend more to establish greater control. For example, a minor lord would have Maximum
Influence of 40, a great lord would have Maximum Influence of 50).</Benefit>
<Special>Your title may need to be confirmed by your vassal lord (either a great lord or by the
king himself). In your territory, you have the potential for tremendous power (see Maximum
Influence, page 191), and you may have other rights and privileges (such as the ability to
dispense the king’s justice), depending on your house’s position.
This Feat should also be used to raise a member of the royal family (Social Status Rank
5) from crown prince (Heir) to king of the realm (whose Maximum Influence is 60), and a
Dothraki khalakka to khal.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Heir</Name>
<Description>You are the first born child, or somehow otherwise acknowledged as heir to a noble
house.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Social Status 3+
GM’s approval</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+5 Influence over house</Abstract><Benefit>You have greater Influence over your house than your siblings. You gain 5 Influence
Points over your house. Although you now have greater sway over the house, you also have
more responsibilities towards it.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Hero’s Effort</Name>
<Description>You possess near bottomless reserves of willpower, stamina, and energy. Tapping into
them allows you to push yourself to the limit of human abilities, and even beyond.</Description>
<Abstract>one additional AT/4 lvls</Abstract><Benefit>Once per day for every four character Levels, you may take one additional action in a
combat round. The action can be either a non-combat action or an attack action, and may
come before or after your normal actions. However many times you may use Hero’s Effort in
a day, though, you can never use it more than once per combat round.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Initiative (Improved)</Name>
<Description>Finely honed reflexes allow you to react more quickly than normal in a fight.</Description>
<Abstract>+4 bonus Initiative</Abstract><Benefit>You receive a +4 bonus to all Initiative checks. This stacks with any other bonus to
Initiative.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Iron Will</Name>
<Description>You have a stronger will than normal.</Description>
<Abstract>+2 bonus Will Saves</Abstract><Benefit>You receive a +2 bonus to Will Saves.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Knockout Punch</Name>
<Description>You are skilled at delivering a stunning blow to unwary opponents.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Brawl
Base Attack Bonus +3</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>first AT = critical hit</Abstract><Benefit>When making your first unarmed attack against a flat-footed opponent, treat a successful
attack as a critical hit. This damage is nonlethal damage.</Benefit>
<Special>Even if you have the ability to treat unarmed damage as lethal damage, the damage from
a knockout punch is always nonlethal.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Knockout Punch (Improved)</Name>
<Description>You have refined your knockout bunch to devastating effect.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Brawl
Knockout Punch
Base Attack Bonus +6</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>first AT = critical hit
3*damage</Abstract><Benefit>When making your first unarmed attack against a flat-footed opponent, treat a successful
attack as a critical hit. This critical hit deals triple damage. This damage is nonlethal.</Benefit>
<Special>Even if you have the ability to treat unarmed damage as lethal damage, the damage from
a knockout punch is always nonlethal.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Leechcraft</Name>
<Description>Long study of the healer’s craft allows you to provide extraordinary care to the injured.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Heal 4 Ranks</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>restore additional hitpoint</Abstract><Benefit>This Feat allows the character to use the Heal Skill to restore an additional number of
Hit Points through the use of more extensive and thorough procedures. You must have the
proper implements (knives, bandages, boiled wine, herbs, etc) and sufficient time to work.
You can perform leechcraft on yourself, but at a -5 penalty.
The Heal check takes roughly an hour, and possibly much longer to tend grievous
wounds (the exact time is at GM’s discretion). To determine the results of the check, consult
the table 8-2. Only one successful leechcraft attempt can ever be made on an injured
character per week.</Benefit>
<Special>If the Heal check is successful, and the patient stays in the healer’s care for a full day
or more, he or she is considered to be recovering at double the normal rate (see Recovering
Hit Points, page 258).</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Lightning Reflexes</Name>
<Description>You have faster than normal reflexes.</Description>
<Abstract>+2 bouns Reflex Saves</Abstract><Benefit>You gain a +2 bonus to all Reflex Saves.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Literacy</Name>
<Description>You are lettered, which is a talent unknown to many of the smallfolk.</Description>
<Abstract>read &amp; write native tongue</Abstract><Benefit>You can read and write your native tongue.</Benefit>
<Special>In order to become literate in foreign languages, you must first have at least 1 Rank in
Speak Language. You may spend 1 additional Skill Point to become literate with a language
you know. Each language requires a separate expenditure.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Mounted Archery</Name>
<Description>You are skilled at using missile weapons from horseback.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Ride 1 Rank
Mounted Warrior</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>half penalty</Abstract><Benefit>
The penalty you suffer when using a ranged weapon from horseback is halved: -2 if the
mount is moving normally, -3 if the mount is cantering, and -4 if the mount is running. See
Mounted Combat, page 247, for more information.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Mounted Archery (Improved)</Name>
<Description>You are exceptionally skilled at using missile weapons from horseback.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Ride 4 Ranks
Mounted Archery
Mounted Warrior</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>no penalties</Abstract><Benefit>You do not suffer any penalties when using a ranged weapon from horseback.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Mounted Warrior</Name>
<Description>Like the infamous Dothraki nomads and the famed knights of Westeros, you are skilled
at fighting from the back of a horse.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Ride 1 Rank</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>replace horse AC</Abstract><Benefit>During combat, when your mount is threatened by an attack, you may choose to
replace the horse’s Armour Class with a value equal to your total Ride Skill (Ride Skill +
Dex Modifier + Class Modifiers). This value (as a static number), becomes the horse’s new
Armour Class. Multiple attacks will impose a cumulative -2 penalty on the Armour Class.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Parry</Name>
<Description>You are skilled at defending yourself with a weapon.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon
Base Attack Bonus +1</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+1 (+2) defence roll</Abstract><Benefit>Choose one type of weapon. You gain a +1 to defence rolls when defending with that
weapon against one specific opponent. You may specify the target at the beginning of each
combat round, and may select a new opponent every action. A character in no armour or light
armour defends at +2. You cannot parry missile weapons, however.</Benefit>
<Special>Parry bonuses stack with all other defence check bonuses. This Feat may be taken
multiple times. Each time, it applies to a different weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Parry (Improved)</Name>
<Description>You have gained mastery at defending yourself with a weapon.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Parry
Base Attack Bonus +4</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+2 defence roll</Abstract><Benefit>Choose one type of weapon for which you have already selected Parry. You gain a +2
bonus on all defence rolls you make using the selected weapon, as long as you are wearing no
armour or light armour. You cannot parry missile weapons, however.</Benefit>
<Special>Parry (Improved) bonuses stack with all other defence check bonuses. This Feat may
be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to a different weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Point Blank Shot</Name>
<Description>You can make well-placed shots with missile weapons at close range.</Description>
<Abstract>AT &amp; dam +1 </Abstract><Benefit>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls while using any missile weapon on a
foe within 30 feet.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Political Connections</Name>
<Description>Whether through force of personality, guile, or position, you have managed to become
an influential player in the game of thrones.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Cha 13
Diplomacy, Bluff, or Intimidate 4 Ranks</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>IP +4 +Cha bonus</Abstract><Benefit>You receive 4 + Cha Modifier (minimum of +0) bonus Influence Points. These may be
spent on house or organisational Influences, on personal Influences, or on Secret Influences.
See page 189 for more information about Influence.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Power Attack</Name>
<Description>You’ve learned to put all of your body’s Strength into a swing, making powerful (though
somewhat clumsy) attacks.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Str 13</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>-x AT = +x dam</Abstract><Benefit>On your action, but before attacking in a round, you may choose to subtract a number
from all melee attack rolls made that round and add the same number to all melee damage
rolls. The number of points shifted from attack to damage cannot exceed your Base Attack
Bonus. The bonus to damage and penalty to attack apply until your next action. Note: you
cannot apply Accuracy to a Power Attack due to the wild nature of the attack, nor can you
combine a Power Attack with Combat Expertise, Fighting Defensively, etc.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Precise Shot</Name>
<Description>You are skilled at timing and aiming ranged attacks.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Point Blank Shot</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>hit target in melee w/o penalty</Abstract><Benefit>You can shoot or throw a missile weapon at a target engaged in melee combat without
suffering the usual -4 penalty (see Shooting or Throwing into Melee, page 237).</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Quick Witted</Name>
<Description>Your mind moves quickly, and you are always ready to react.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Wis 13</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>Initiative + Wis bonus</Abstract><Benefit>You can add your Wis bonus to Initiative rolls.</Benefit>
<Special>These effects stack with any other bonus for Initiative rolls.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Raised Status</Name>
<Description>The patronage of the powerful has allowed you to climb socially, attaining a higher
status than you were born into.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Reputation +1
powerful patron or ally
GM’s approval</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+5 IP</Abstract><Benefit>You have gained 5 Influence Points over one organisation or house. Although you now
have greater sway over the organisation or house, you also have more responsibilities towards
it, and may be called upon for service.</Benefit>
<Special>If these are your first Influence Points with the organisation, you are recognised as a
junior member. If you also take the Wealth Feat (page 182), your character’s Social Status
Rank (page 90) may increase. Between this Feat and Wealth, you may acquire up to Social
Status Rank 2. GM’s should normally not allow characters to raise their Social Status
beyond Rank 2 unless it is good for the story. Characters who might be appropriate for this
application include the Queen, the King’s Hand, Bloodriders, etc.
You can take this Feat multiple times, with GM’s approval. Its effects normally stack,
although if you have Influence over multiple organisations or houses, you may decide where the
5 Points area allocated (all 5 must be assigned to the same place, however). You cannot exceed
the Maximum Influence value listed for an organisation or house (page 191).</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Ride-By Attack</Name>
<Description>You are trained to strike a target from the back of your horse, and continue on out of
the target’s reach.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Ride 1 Rank
Mounted Warrior</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>engage, hit and run one action</Abstract><Benefit>When you are mounted and use the charge action, you may move and attack as if with
a standard charge and then move again (continuing the straight line of the charge), to distance
yourself from the target. Your total movement for the round can’t exceed double your mounted
speed.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Run</Name>
<Description>You are fleet of foot.</Description>
<Abstract>Speed *5 (*4)
+4 bonus Jump check</Abstract><Benefit>When running, you move five times your normal speed (if wearing light or no armour
and carrying no more than a light load) or four times your speed (if wearing medium or heavy
armour or carrying a medium or heavy load). If you make a jump after a running start (see
the Jump Skill), you gain a +4 bonus on your Jump check. While running, you retain your
Dexterity bonus to AC.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Shield Proficiency</Name>
<Description>You are proficient at fighting with a shield.</Description>
<Abstract>no penalties to AT and movement skills</Abstract><Benefit>You can use a shield for its full AC bonus, and do not suffer armour check penalties to
attacks and movement based Skills (see Armour, page 211).</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Skill Mastery</Name>
<Description>You’re a fast learner and show aptitude with a wide range of Skill.</Description>
<Abstract>+9 SP</Abstract><Benefit>You receive 9 Skill Points to spend on your Skills as you choose. The points may be
spent on one Skill or spread among several, but Skills cannot be raised above the maximum
based on your current Level.</Benefit>
<Special>You may gain this Feat multiple times. Its effects stack, within the limits described.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Spirited Charge</Name>
<Description>You are trained at making a devastating mounted charge.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Ride 4 Ranks
Mounted Warrior</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>2*dam melee
3*dam lance</Abstract><Benefit>When mounted and using the charge option, you deal double damage with a melee
weapon or triple damage with a lance.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Stern Visage</Name>
<Description>You have cultivated the ability to frighten those around you with the power of your
voice, presence, or gaze.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Cha 13 or Str 13
Intimidate 9 Ranks.</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract><Benefit>Once per round as a free action, you can try to unnerve everyone around you. All
opponents within 30 feet who have fewer Character Levels (including ECLs) than you must
make a Will Save (DC = 10 +1/2 your Level + Cha or Str Modifier). Additionally, if your
Reputation is applicable, add half your Reputation value to the DC. Opponents who fail
their Saves are shaken, suffering a -2 to all attack rolls, Saves, and Skill checks for a number
of rounds equal to double your Cha or Str Modifier (minimum of 2). Opponents who
successfully Save are immune to your Stern Visage for a full day.</Benefit>
<Special>Outside combat, subjects remain terrified as long as they are in your presence.
The Ignoble or Marked disadvantages can each increase the DC of the Save by +2, at
the GM’s discretion.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Streetfighting</Name>
<Description>The alleys and back rooms of King’s Landing and every great city are filled with feral
killers, murderers who fight with all the savagery of dogs and the cunning of rats. You’ve
learned all their tricks.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Brawl
Base Attack Bonus +2</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>dam +d4</Abstract><Benefit>When unarmed or fighting with a light weapon (see page 206), you may add an
additional 1d4 to the damage of one attack, once per round.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Tactics</Name>
<Description>Your Intelligence and knowledge gives you an edge in combat.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Int 13</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>AT or PA + Int bonus</Abstract><Benefit>Select one weapon. When using that weapon, you may opt to add your Int bonus to
attack rolls or defence rolls, chosen when this Feat is first selected.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to either the alternate
value (attack or defence) or a different weapon. Its effect do not stack with Bravado, Brute,
Canny, or Finesse.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Tough</Name>
<Description>You are tougher than normal, making you hard to kill.</Description>
<Abstract>+2 HP, +1 SV</Abstract><Benefit>You gain +2 Hit Points, and +1 Shock Value.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Its effects stack.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Trip (Improved)</Name>
<Description>You are trained to quickly follow through with an attack if your opponent trips.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Int 13
Combat Expertise</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+4 Strength check trip</Abstract><Benefit>You gain a +4 bonus to your Strength check to trip an opponent. If you trip an
opponent in melee combat, you immediately get to make a melee attack against that opponent
as if you had not used your attack action for the trip attempt.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Two-Weapon Defence</Name>
<Description>You have learned to parry with an off-hand weapon.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Two-Weapon Fighting</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+1 Defence bonus</Abstract><Benefit>When fighting with two weapons, you gain a +1 Defence Bonus. If fighting defensively
or using the total defence action, this bonus increases to +2.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Two-Weapon Fighting</Name>
<Description>Training and practice allow you to fight comfortably with a weapon in both hands.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Dex 15</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>penalties reduced 2/6</Abstract><Benefit>Your penalties for fighting with two weapons are reduced. The penalty for your primary
weapon is reduced by 2, and the penalty for your secondary weapon is reduced by 6.</Benefit>
<Special>If your off-hand weapon is light the penalties are reduced by 2 each. (An unarmed strike
is always considered light.)</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Two-Weapon Fighting (Improved)</Name>
<Description>You are an expert at fighting with a weapon in each hand.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Dex 17
Two-Weapon Fighting
Base Attack Bonus +6</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+1 off hand AT</Abstract><Benefit>In addition to the single extra attack you gain with an off-hand weapon, you gain an
additional attack with the off-hand weapon, but at a -5 penalty. The normal penalties for
attacking with two weapons still apply (see Two Weapon Fighting Penalties, page 241).</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Veteran</Name>
<Description>You’ve already seen battle, perhaps as a militiaman, sellsword, or even in the army of a
great house. You know how to fight with the ferocity of a wild animal, and foes find it difficult
to catch you off your guard.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected weapon
Base Attack Bonus +6.</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>Opponent SV -2</Abstract><Benefit>A specific type of weapon must be chosen when this Feat is taken. When you attack with
this weapon, the opponent’s Shock Value is reduced by 2.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Wealth</Name>
<Description>Wealth is an indication of assets, holdings, and incomes to which you have access.
Wealth represents more than simple coinage, but it is ultimately an expression of how much
you can draw upon to pursue your agenda. A peasant may perhaps have only enough Wealth
to feed himself and his family, while a great lord may have enough Wealth to feed and equip
tens of thousands of soldiers.</Description>
<Prerequisites>GM’s approval</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>Wealth +1</Abstract><Benefit>Your Wealth is considered to be +1 Rank. The exact effects are determined by your total
Wealth Rank, but suggest you have monetary resources or tangible assets at hand. Wealth is
akin to an absolute resource, unlike Influence Points, and its effects are more specific. You can
spend your resources in any way you choose, but companionship acquired in this manner is
loyalty bought by the coin. It has no lasting commitment.
Wealth for small purchases is normally drawn against the resources of your house or
lands (or if a great merchant, other properties). Wealth can be temporarily decreased, but it
is normally a robust asset that will replenish over time. See page 203 for more information
on Wealth.</Benefit>
<Special>Each character has a Wealth Rank tied initially to his or her Social Status Rank.
By taking the Feat Wealth, a character achieves greater financial resources than he or she
first started the game with. This can only be done when it fits the story, and with GM’s
permission.
If a character takes the Wealth Feat and the Raised Status Feat, his or her Social Status
may also increase. Between this Feat and Raised Status, you may acquire up to Social Status
Rank 2. GM’s should normally not allow characters to raise their Social Status beyond Rank
2 unless it is good for the story.
This Feat can be taken multiple times. Its effects stack, but should normally be limited
to an absolute Wealth Rank of 6.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Weapon Focus</Name>
<Description>You favour one type of weapon, and have practised with it to an extraordinary degree
of mastery.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Proficiency with selected weapon
Base Attack Bonus +1</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>AT +1 bonus</Abstract><Benefit>Choose one type of weapon. You gain a +1 bonus to all attack rolls when wielding that
weapon type.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time, you must
apply it to a new type of weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Weapon Focus (Greater)</Name>
<Description>You have become terrifying with your weapon of choice.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Weapon Focus with selected weapon
Base Attack Bonus +8</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>AT +1 bonus</Abstract><Benefit>Choose one type of weapon for which you have already selected Weapon Focus. You
gain a +1 bonus on all attack rolls you make using the selected weapon. This bonus stacks with
other bonuses on attack rolls, including the one from Weapon Focus.</Benefit>
<Special>You can gain Greater Weapon Focus multiple times. Its effects do not stack. Each time
you take the Feat, it applies to a new type of weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Weapon Proficiency (Exotic)</Name>
<Description>You have learned how to use an exotic weapon, such as the whip or one-handed bastard
sword. This Feat can also represent training in the use of obsidian weapons.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Base Attack Bonus +1</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>AT at full AT bonus</Abstract><Benefit>Select one type of exotic weapon (see Table 11-7: Weapons, on page 210 for more
information). When using that weapon, you make attacks at your full attack bonus.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to a different weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Weapon Proficiency (Martial)</Name>
<Description>You have learned to use a martial weapon, such as a longbow or longsword.</Description>
<Abstract>AT at full AT bonus</Abstract><Benefit>Select one type of martial weapon (see Table 11-7: Weapons, on page 210 for more
information). When using that weapon, you make attacks at your full attack bonus. This Feat
can be used to expand your proficient weapons beyond the list in the basic Class description.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to a different weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Weapon Proficiency (Simple)</Name>
<Description>You have learned to use simple weapons, such as spears, daggers, and clubs.</Description>
<Abstract>AT at full AT bonus</Abstract><Benefit>When using simple weapons (page 206) you attack at your full attack bonus.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Weapon Specialisation</Name>
<Description>Your growing mastery of a favoured weapon lets you deal out far more damage in
combat.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Proficient with weapon
Base Attack Bonus +4
Weapon Focus</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+2 dam</Abstract><Benefit>Choose one type of weapon for which you have already selected the Weapon Focus Feat.
You gain a +2 to all damage rolls with that weapon.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, it applies to a different weapon.</Special>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>G</Type>
    <Name>Whirlwind Attack</Name>
<Description>With all the speed and grace of a Water Dancer, you can strike nearby opponents in an
amazing, spinning attack.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Dex 13
Int 13
Combat Agility
Combat Expertise
Dodge
Veteran</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract><Benefit>In a single combat round, you can choose to forgo your regular attacks and instead
make one melee attack at your full attack bonus against every foe within 5 feet.</Benefit>
</Feat>
  <Feat>
    <Type>L</Type>
    <Name>Animal Companion</Name>
<Description>You have forged a deep, supernatural bond with an animal. The beast’s spirit is part of
you, and your spirit is part of it.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Blood of First Men or Blood of the Dragon.
At the GM’s discretion, other Blood Feats
may also grant access to this Feat.</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You gain the friendship and loyalty of one animal. The animal must be iconic to
the character’s house, land, or tribe (direwolves for members of House Stark, dragons for
members of House Targaryen, bears, wolves, or shadowcats for Wildlings, etc.). The animal’s
loyalty lasts only so long as you honestly intends to be that animal’s friend; abuse will sever
the bond immediately.
The companion animal will respond to your vocal commands. You may teach the
animal three tricks or tasks per point of Intelligence the animal possesses. Typical tricks
include coming when called, fetching, breaking off from combat, staying, etc. The tasks cannot
be complex. Teaching the animal to accept a rider (assuming it is of a size to do so) requires
the use of the Handle Animal Skill.
The animal will always look out for your well being, attacking anyone who menaces or
threatens you without hesitation. The beast will also show a profound dislike for anyone whom
you distrust or who might bear you ill will. Over time, your companion animal will become
acutely connected to your emotional state, growing agitated when you are upset and playful
when you are happy.
The link goes both ways, however. Prolonged separation from your companion animal
leads to melancholy, while the death of the animal provokes a deep depression.</Benefit>
<Special>If an animal companion is killed or lost, the GM may let you select another Feat. This
may even include a new animal companion, if appropriate to the story.</Special>
</Feat>
 <Feat>
    <Type>L</Type>
    <Name>Dreams</Name>
<Prerequisites>Wis 15
Appropriate Blood Feat (Blood of the First Men; Blood of the Dragon,
Dothraki Born) or regional Background (North, the Wild).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You sometimes dream true. In certain dreams, you can see hints of the future. Most
such visions come involuntarily (at the GM’s discretion), but if you are particularly concerned
about a loved one, or otherwise experiencing strong emotions, you may experience such a
dream (if the player convinces the GM to allow a check, he or she must make a Wisdom check
at DC 20. If the characters share a sympathetic tie through Blood Feats, the GM may allow a
bonus). These dreams reveal short glimpses of the future, often cloaked in obscure metaphor.
The GM must create and describe the vision. Normally, a character should not have a true
dream more than once per session, and perhaps even less frequently.
These visions can be treacherous: they rarely signify what they seem to and can rarely
be interpreted literally. A vision of another character’s death, for example, may indicate only
the intent to harm that person, a future loss of status or reputation, or even that the world at
large may soon come to believe that the prophesied victim is dead. An invasion might appear
as a storm coming from a specifi c direction that batters down castles and ravages fi elds. Even
specifi c people may be cloaked in metaphor: a Lannister prince might appear as a great lion
with bloody jaws, for example, or a treacherous man as a serpent.
Not all dreams are true. You may, if bewildered by the strange symbols of a dream, try
to interpret them by making a Knowledge: Arcana check (DC 25). If successful, the GM will
confi rm the nature of the dream and may (at his or her discretion) give a single hint of the
vision’s meaning. True dreams often show events whose origins are not easily determined, or
ones that, once set in motion, are impossible to stop. No one knows for certain whether true
dreams are set in stone, or whether the future can be changed.</Benefit>
</Feat>
 <Feat>
    <Type>L</Type>
    <Name>Pious</Name>
	<Description>The Seven Gods of the Andals watch over their children. Your faith and devoted service
to the Seven has created a special link between you and the gods. So long as your faith remains
true, your prayers will be heard — and may even be answered.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Wis 15
Appropriate regional Background (The Reach, the Riverlands, the Stormlands,
the Westerlands, the Vale of Arryn)
Blood of the Andals
Knowledge: Religion (the Seven) 3 Ranks</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You may pray to the Seven for guidance and aid. Unlike the blessing that septons
can call upon, this Feat allows anyone who worships the Seven to turn to them for aid and
intervention. Always bear in mind that these invoked miracles are not spells, and may be
fundamentally similar to the faith-based blessings that Godsworn septons and septa can
provide.
To gain the attention and favour of the Seven, you must recite a prayer to one of the
Seven asking for guidance or help with a specifi c problem or endeavour. The prayer and the
problem must be both be appropriate to the aspect of the Seven invoked. The Mother, for
example, can be invoked to keep soldiers (every one of them someone’s son) safe in battle,
but cannot bring victory — the Warrior must be prayed to for that. The Seven Who are One,
on page 351, describes the attributes and aspects of the Seven in more detail. You must have
demonstrated your faith to the Seven clearly in both word and deed before there is even any
hope of invoking the aid of the Seven. The request must also be worthwhile.
If you are worthy and the need is great (both at the GM’s discretion), you may make a
Wisdom check to see if your prayer is heard. The Modifi ers to this check, and its results, are
described on the tables below:
The intervention of the Seven should always be subtle and indirect. GMs should use
divine insights and interventions as plot devices, helping to drive campaigns and reward strong
role-playing. There should always be a “logical explanation” that also accounts for the outcome
of the prayer. The Seven rarely speak with voices mortal men can hear, and even then their
voices are heard in dreams or fever visions. Even the most pious usually have cause to wonder
if the Seven have intervened at all.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Able Body</Name>
<Description>Arising from a noteworthy Dexterity or Strength (or both), you are gifted with a knack
for physical and athletic pursuits.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Str 13 or Dex 13
Appropriate House Affiliation (Arryn, Greyjoy, Martell, Tyrell, No
House)
or regional Background (Dorne, the Iron Islands, the Reach).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Select any two Skills from the following list that you do not have as Class Skills.
These Skills will now always count as Class Skills. Skills that may be chosen by this Feat
are as follows: Balance, Climb, Escape Artist, Hide, Move Silently, Ride, Swim, Tumble,
and Use Rope.</Benefit>
<Special>Characters may take this Feat more than once, choosing new Skills each time.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>As High As Honour</Name>
<Description>The honour of House Arryn is very nearly unimpeachable. Anyone wishing to smear an
Arryn’s good name had best have rock-solid evidence, or the kind of spy network most great
factions can only dream of.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Arryn).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+2 one Reputation</Abstract>
<Benefit>You gain +2 Points to one Reputation, so long as that Reputation is one that is not
in conflict with your house motto. For example, Honourable, Honest, Generous, Fierce,
Loyal, or Valorous would all be acceptable Reputations; Honey-tongued, Sneaky, or Wild
would not.
Furthermore, anyone attempting to besmirch your good name or turn another character
against you (for example using Influence, Little Birds, or any social Skill checks) does so at
a penalty of -5.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Blood of the Andals</Name>
<Description>Fair-haired and fierce, the Andals came to the lands of Westeros at the end of the Age
of Heroes, bringing with them steel and the worship of the Seven. As diverse in their talents
as the seven gods they venerated, the Andals spread over the face of Westeros, conquering all
of it save the North. The blood of those ancient heroes flows true in your veins, giving you
talents beyond those of lesser men.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Arryn, Baratheon, Frey, Lannister, Tully, Tyrell)
or regional Background (the Reach, the Riverlands, the Stormlands, the Westerlands, the Vale
of Arryn).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>+1 to all Ability-based Skill checks</Abstract>
<Benefit>You receive a +1 to all Ability-based Skill checks based upon a specific Ability (Str,
Int, etc.) that is chosen at the time the Feat is taken. The favoured Ability must be chosen at
character creation and may never be changed. Additionally, you may have an intuitive link to
the members of your family (see sidebar, Intuitive Family Links, page 167).</Benefit>
<Special>
This Feat may only be taken at 1st Level. Only one blood Feat may be taken by any
character.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Blood of the Dragon</Name>
<Description>You are a scion of House Targaryen, invaders who rode dragons and conquered and
united the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros centuries ago. The blood of the Dragon stems from
the high lords of ancient Valyria, who worshipped no gods and worked ancient magics before
the Doom overtook them.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Targaryen).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Legend has it that dragon fire flows in the veins of Valyrian trueborn. You may make a
Will Save (at DC 15) to ignore heat or fire damage (up to 10 damage per round), as Daenerys
did at the birth of her dragons. The blood of old Valyria also brings with it profound strength
of will: you may add your Charisma bonus (minimum +1) to any d20 roll, once per day (you
can decide after you roll). Additionally, you may have an intuitive link to the members of your
family (see sidebar, Intuitive Family Links, page 167).</Benefit>
<Special>
This Feat may only be taken at 1st Level. Only one blood Feat may be taken by any
character. Additionally, depending on the era of the campaign, GM approval may be required
to select his Feat.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Blood of the First Men</Name>
<Description>The First Men came to Westeros in the Age of Dawn, bearing weapons of bronze and
great leather shields. They fought ancient wars with the children of the forest, until they forged
the Pact and took up worship of the old gods at the beginning of the Age of Heroes. In the
ancient realms of the North, the blood of the First Men still flows true; their faith in the old
gods has always served them.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Stark, Umber)
or regional Background (the North).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Born to the harsh climes of the North, you receive a +1 to all Fortitude Saves. The
wisdom and traditions of the First Men serve you well — you may add your Wisdom bonus
(minimum +1) to any d20 roll, once per day (you can decide after you roll). Additionally,
you may have an intuitive link to the members of your family (see sidebar, Intuitive Family
Links, right column).</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may only be taken at 1st Level. Only one blood Feat may be taken by any
character.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>blood of the Ironborn</Name>
<Description>The men of the Iron Islands have been feared for thousands of years, as fierce raiders
who ply the seas and worship their terrible Drowned God. These hard folk are supposedly
descended from the legendary Grey King. They had once carved out kingdoms on the
mainland of Westeros, but were eventually conquered by the Targaryens. Since that time, their
infl uence has retreated to the Iron Islands, but there the true Ironborn still dwell, strong and
spiteful. You may call yourself Ironborn, no doubt with pride.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affi liation (Greyjoy)
or regional Background (the Iron Islands).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>The pitiless clime of the Iron Islands breeds sturdy men indeed: you receive a +1 bonus
to all Fortitude Saves. The harsh land forces you to adapt and survive — you may add your
Constitution bonus (minimum +1) to any d20 roll, once per day (you can decide after you
roll). Additionally, you may have an intuitive link to the members of your family (see sidebar,
Intuitive Family Links, right column).</Benefit>
<Special>
This Feat must be taken at 1st Level. Only one blood Feat may be taken by any
character.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Blood of the Rhoyne</Name>
<Description>A dark-skinned folk from foreign shores, the Rhoyne came to Westeros in a fleet of
10,000 ships, led by the legendary warrior queen, Nymeria. The Rhoynish folk secured the
crown of Dorne through marriage and have ruled the southern realm ever since. Language,
law, and custom set the Rhoyne apart from the other peoples of Westeros. The fiery Rhoynish
blood shows true in your family, making you a force to be reckoned with.</Description>
<Prerequisites>
Appropriate House Affi liation (Martell)
or regional Background (Dorne).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>The competitive nature of the Rhoyne gives you a +1 bonus to all non-combat related
opposed Skill and Ability checks (this would give a bonus to Listen vs. Move Silently,
for example, but not to overhear a noise in the distance). This does not include the use of
Infl uence. Additionally, you may have an intuitive link to the members of your family (see
sidebar, Intuitive Family Links, right column).</Benefit>
<Special>
This Feat must be taken at 1st Level. Only one blood Feat may be taken by any
character.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Dothraki Born/Name></Name>
<Description>This is a Blood Feat. The Dothraki ride from a very early age, taking to the saddle as if
they were born to it. They are masters of the horse, and ride better than any Westerosi.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate regional Background (Dothraki).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Early familiarity and constant experience makes you especially adept with horses. You
receive a +4 bonus to Ride checks, and gain a +1 Defence Bonus when mounted and wearing
no armour.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat must be taken at 1st Level. Only one blood Feat may be taken by any
character.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Family, Duty, Honour</Name>
<Description>House Tully has always considered that the fi rst duty of its scions is to their immediate
family — perhaps even before their duty to the house as a whole. No Tully is ever likely to be
punished by the head of the house for helping out a brother or sister, even when that sibling
was in the wrong.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (House Tully).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>When you successfully perform the aid another action (page 237) for another character who
has House Affi liation Tully, or is a sworn bannerhouse to Tully, he or she gains a +4 bonus to the
task rather than the usual +2 (for example, the target could gain a +4 to an attack or defence roll,
or to a Skill check). Furthermore, if he or she succeeds at the task, you gain a +1 bonus on all
attack rolls, damage rolls, defence rolls, and Saving Throws you make in the following round. If
the character you aid is a member of your immediate family (parent, sibling, or child), the target
receives a +6 on the aided task, and if successful, you gain a +2 on rolls the following round.</Benefit>
<Special>In a campaign in which all the characters are siblings of House Tully, the GM may wish
to reduce the effects of this Feat, perhaps cancelling the increased benefi ts for aiding members
of the immediate family.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Fire And Blood</Name>
<Description>A wounded dragon is at its most dangerous, full of anger and ready to strike out to
slay its tormentors.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Targaryen).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>On any round in which you sustain an injury from a melee combat attack, you may
make enter a state of cold, calculating anger. When angry, you gain a +2 bonus on damage
rolls when making a melee attack anyone who has injured you, and you can make an additional
attack each round against them at your full attack bonus. Any attacks you make while angered
against a character who has not injured you are at a -2 penalty on attack and damage rolls. Your
state of anger ends as soon as all those who have injured you are dead or no longer in sight.
You may enter a state of anger up to a number of times per day equal to 1 + your Wisdom
Modifier (minimum 1).</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Giant’s Blood (Optional Feat)</Name>
<Description>Giants are fi erce things, all hair and teeth, where the women have beards as great as their
husbands. Sometimes the women take human men for lovers, and give birth to the half-bloods.
Giant’s Blood is a thing of the north, but it may carry for several generations, granting children
powerful limbs and a towering stature.</Description>
<Prerequisites>
Appropriate House Affiliation (the Vale of Arryn, Baratheon, Umber, No House)
or regional Background (the North, the Stormlands, the Westerlands, the Wild).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Born with the blood of a giant running through your veins, you are tremendously hardy
and strong, receiving a +4 Str and +2 Con. Additionally, whenever you are subject to a size
modifi er (such as during grapple checks, trip attempts, or during some special attack checks)
you are treated as one size larger if doing so is benefi cial to you. Your great size does not come
without cost, however, and thus you suffer a -4 penalty to Dex. At over six and a half feet,
you can wield two-handed weapons in one hand; and armour (and some weapons) cost 150%
— 200% more than usual, and must be specially made to fit.</Benefit>
<Special>This Feat may only be taken at 1st Level. Giant’s Blood counts as a blood Feat and
may not be taken in conjunction with any other bloodline Feat. Additionally, characters with
Giant’s Blood are so exceptionally powerful in combat that they should be regarded as ECL
+1. GMs may wish to limit the amount of Giant’s Blood characters in the campaign, or may
even waive the ECL Modifi er if combat will not be a substantial part of the game.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Gold Breeder</Name>
<Description>You have a talent for raising and managing vast sums. Some say that you can create a
shower of golden coins simply by rubbing two together. In truth, you have a talent for sums
and a knack for juggling loans, debts, and usury. Such talents would make you an invaluable
addition to any household or court.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Int 13, Appropriate House Affiliation (Arryn, Lannister, Martell, Tyrell)
or regional
Background (Dorne, the Free Cities, King’s Landing, the Reach, the Vale of Arryn, the
Westerlands).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You receive a +2 bonus to any rolls made to raise money, or in any transactions
dependent upon Wealth. Additionally, the amount of money raised by any Skill or Infl uence
check is increased by an amount equal to your Int Modifier x 20%.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Growing Strong</Name>
<Description>The Tyrells long ago learned to apply the principles of hard work and an eventual harvest
to many other fields, including warfare and politics.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Tyrell).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You may spend one week to define a particular goal you wish to achieve, and a plan to
achieve it. Whenever you are working towards your goal and in accordance with your plan, you
gain a +1 bonus on all directly relevant Skill checks, attack rolls, and damage rolls. The GM
will decide whether you are fulfilling these requirements with regard to any particular roll.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Hear Me Roar</Name>
<Description>The Lannisters are feared throughout Westeros, not just because of their prowess in
battle but because of what they will do to the opposition’s survivors and kin once victorious.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Lannister).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Once per melee combat, you may make use of the Intimidate Skill to Demoralise
Opponent (see Intimidate, page 156) as a free action instead of as a standard action. The
opponent must be aware that you are a Lannister, and you must be capable of shouting (this
could be a battle cry, threat, or just a wordless roar).</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Keen Mind</Name>
<Description>Sharp senses, quick wits, and sound faculties combine to give you a knack for
discerning, learning, and remembering.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Int 13 or Wis 13, Appropriate House Affiliation (Frey, Tully, Tyrell, No House) 
or regional Background (Free Cities, the Reach, the Riverlands).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Select any two Skills from the following list that you do not have as Class Skills. These
Skills now always count as Class Skills. The following Skills are available: Appraise, Decipher
Script, Forgery, Heal, Knowledge (Any), Listen, Sense Motive, Spot.</Benefit>
<Special>You may take this Feat more than once, but must choose two new Skills from the list
each time.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Noble Spirit</Name>
<Description>Something in your mien inspires intense loyalty.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Cha 13
Appropriate House Affiliation (Arryn, Baratheon, Stark, No House)
or regional Background (the North, the Stormlands, the Vale of Arryn).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You form a deep bond of friendship and trust with one friend, companion, or follower,
selected at the time the Feat is assigned. That character becomes a true companion and will
never willingly betray you of his or her own accord. Any attempts to trick this companion into
a betrayal suffer a -10 penalty to any social Skill checks or Influence rolls. Additionally, you
can call upon your ally for aid in times of need, although this is a resource that should not be
abused or taken lightly. The friendship should be considered mutual, and the friend may call
upon you for help at times. GMs should determine what help can be provided as appropriate
to the particular character.
The GM may, at his or her discretion, require an episode of intense role-play or some
meaningful action from you for this Feat to take effect. The Greatjon’s confrontation with
Robb Stark and his direwolf, Grey Wind, is an excellent example.
The effects of this Feat last as long as the companion lives. If the loyal companion is
slain, you may apply this Feat to a different character (although an appropriate role-playing
encounter may be required). Conversely, if you betray the friend the Feat is lost.</Benefit>
<Special>
This Feat may be taken multiple times. Each time, you must apply it to a different
character.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Ours Is The Fury</Name>
<Description>The Baratheons are terrifying in battle, filled with a righteous fury that makes them
almost unstoppable.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Baratheon).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You are extremely stubborn, and that stubbornness can burst into fiery anger. You gain
+1 to Will Saves. In addition, you may fly into a rage, gaining a +2 to Strength, and +2 to
attack rolls, but suffering a -2 to Armour Class. A fit of rage lasts for a number of rounds
equal to 3 + Constitution Modifier (minimum of 3). At the end of the rage, you lose the
rage modifiers and become fatigued for the duration of the current encounter. Entering a rage
takes no time itself, but you can do it only during your action, not in response to someone
else’s action.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Silver Tongue</Name>
<Description>Presence, poise, and demeanour combine to make you an exceptionally persuasive
individual.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Cha 13
Appropriate House Affiliation (Frey, Lannister, Tyrell, No House)
or regional Background (King’s Landing, the Reach, the Riverlands, the Vale of Arryn, the Westerlands).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Select any two Skills from the following list that you do not have as Class Skills. These
Skills now always count as Class Skills. The available Skills are: Bluff, Diplomacy, Disguise,
Gather Information, Handle Animal, Intimidate, Perform (Any).</Benefit>
<Special>You may take this Feat more than once, but must choose two new Skills from the list
each time.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Stubborn</Name>
<Description>The determination of your people is legendary, and you are no exception. You are
extremely headstrong, and it is very difficult to sway you from a decided course.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Baratheon, Greyjoy, Martell, Targaryen, Tully, No
House)
or regional Background (Dorne, Dothraki Sea, the Iron Islands, the Riverlands, the
Stormlands).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You gain a +1 bonus to all Will Saves. Additionally, you gain a +1 Shock Value, as you
aren’t willing to go down easily, and a +1 conditional Fort Save against Shock.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Tradesman</Name>
<Description>You have completed an apprenticeship at a trade, or have spent long hours observing a
master craftsman at work.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Greyjoy, Tully, Umber, No House)
or regional Background (the Iron Islands, the North, the Riverlands).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>Select any two Craft or Profession Skills that you do not have as Class Skills. These
Skills now always count as Class Skills, and you gain a +2 check bonus while using them.</Benefit>
<Special>You may take this Feat more than once. Each selection applies to two new Craft or
Profession specialities.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Twins</Name>
<Description>Freys are a prolific brood, and you almost always have a relative nearby that you can call
upon for aid. He or she is not necessarily loyal to you beyond the ties of blood, and the favour
may likely cost you in the long term.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Frey).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>When you are in need of aid, there is a very high chance a relative will be close by, and
will help you out to the best of his or her ability. This is treated like an Influence check (DC
10), with the following conditions. The help must be logical and appropriate — you should not
make this check if falling down a chasm, or if there is no reasonable way for a relative to be at
hand (you are at sea, beyond the Wall, etc.). You should not make this check more than once
a session (or fortnight, depending on the game timeline).</Benefit>
<Special>Help can take many forms. It may be a haven on the side of the road; an extra sword
in a tavern brawl; passage on a ship; or even a rushed wedding. The GM should ensure the
help gets you out of your particular predicament, but this does not mean it will be in a way
you like or expect. GMs must, however, be careful not to abuse this power, and should use
this Feat as a way to forward the plot or introduce new plot elements. GMs may also use the
results of the Influence check as an indicator of the value of the help (a great success could
mean tremendous aid with few strings attached, while a marginal success could translate into
just enough help at very high cost).
If you do not have the Noble Mandate ability, you gain the ability as a 3rd Level Noble,
but only in regards to asking for assistance from a relative.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Unbowed, Unbent, Unbroken</Name>
<Description>The princes of Dorne are renowned for their willingness to fight on just long enough to
finish the job — even at the cost of their own lives.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Martell).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>When reduced to between -1 and -9 Hit Points, you may choose to act normally, as
though you still had 1 Hit Point or more, although you may still be dying and will continue to
suffer any effects of Serious Injuries that have been inflicted upon you. Once in this state, you
can’t be stunned because of shock. If you reach -10 Hit Points, you immediately die.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Unchained Giant</Name>
<Description>The members of House Umber laugh at pain and revel in physical contests. They are
some of the hardiest men of the North, and their survival depends on their ferocity and resolve.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Umber).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You are harder to shock and gain a +1 to your Shock Value, and a +2 bonus to Fort
Saves made against Shock. Additionally, in battle you can fight beyond 0 Hit Points, only
falling when you reach a negative value equal to double your Con Modifier (min of -2,
maximum of -8). For example, Cley Umber has a Con of 16 (+3 Modifier). He can fight until
he reaches -6 Hit Points, at which time he immediately collapses.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Unknown Heritage</Name>
<Description>You do not know your parentage, and may be a lost heir or somehow else secretly
destined for greatness.</Description>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You do not know some great secret of your past. At an appropriate point in the game,
you may replace this Feat with any other Background Feat. This may only be done in a way
that fits with the story, and with GM’s permission.</Benefit>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>We Do Not Sow</Name>
<Description>The raiders of House Greyjoy were once dreaded in every coastal town. In recent years
the Greyjoys have been held in check somewhat by the power of the King and his supporters,
but with the current crises the ironmen have begun to look at the ripe towns and ports of the
mainland with thoughts of plunder, death, and rapine once more.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Greyjoy).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>If you are leading a group of characters on a raid, the majority of whom have either at
least one Level in the Raider Class or are from the Iron Islands or both, you may set up an
ambush or other surprise attack by taking at least 1 hour to plan and prepare the group. Each
character in the raiding group (including you) gains a +4 bonus to all Hide and Move Silently
checks, and a +4 bonus to Initiative (these stack with other Initiative bonuses), while in or
moving into their designated positions. Additionally, during the first round of the surprise
attack, the characters all gain +2 attack and damage bonuses.</Benefit>
<Special>The player must provide the GM with a complete “plan of attack” covering the intended
actions of all the characters taking part in the attack. Armed with this plan, the GM will be
able to ascertain whether the characters qualify for the various bonuses at any one time.</Special>
</Feat>
<Feat>
    <Type>B</Type>
    <Name>Winter Is Coming</Name>
<Description>The Starks have a reputation for being prepared for anything, and their opponents in
the great game of thrones are often surprised when a Stark seems to have anticipated their
plots and prepared countermeasures, however secretive their plans had been. The Starks are
not actually prepared for everything, but they are capable of considerable foresight when they
set their minds to a particular danger.</Description>
<Prerequisites>Appropriate House Affiliation (Stark).</Prerequisites>
<Abstract>s. Langtext</Abstract>
<Benefit>You may spend one day in preparation for a specific threat. This may be almost any one
thing, but must be specific. For example, you might regard assassination as the greatest danger,
or a Lannister invasion, or the return of the Targaryens from exile, or the coming Winter itself,
or the arrival of the Others out of legend. Once you have defined a threat and prepared for it,
you gain a +2 bonus on all die rolls directly connected with countering the threat or defending
against it. This could include Skill checks, attack rolls, Saving Throws, damage rolls, and
defence rolls, as appropriate.
The GM is always the arbiter as to whether a particular die roll gains the benefit from
this Feat. For example, if you are prepared against assassination, you will gain the benefit of
this Feat on Saving Throws against poison placed in a food specifically to kill you, but not
against the poison inherent in a plant that you eat when lost and hungry in the wilderness
(though you would have gained the bonus if your preparation had been against having to live
rough for a time). Likewise, preparation against assassination will give you bonuses to all
combat-related die rolls when fighting a lone individual who has been tasked to slay you in
your bed, as well as in Skill checks to detect the assassin in the first place, but it will not give
you any bonuses against the attack of a random thief intent on mugging you in Flea Bottom,
or against an enemy met on the battlefield, or against a rival during a bar-room brawl.
Note that this Feat cannot be used offensively — you cannot use it to prepare yourself
to assassinate an enemy, for example.
You may only use this Feat to be prepared for one danger at any one time. However,
you may cancel your preparations to defend against the currently selected threat, then take one
day to prepare against a newly specified threat instead.</Benefit>
</Feat>
</ArrayOfFeat>